<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spencer Braun</title>
    <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Spencer Braun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://spencerbraun.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a graduate student at Stanford, working towards a Master’s in Statistics. My coursework is largely in prediction and machine learning, employing statistical models like regularized linear models and basis expansions as well as deep learning techniques. I have worked on projects in generative language modeling, recommendation systems, experimental design and implementation, tabular data augmentation, and document embeddings. Most recently, I worked at C3.ai for the summer using data science techniques to improve COVID-19 modeling and create publicly available data resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Text Style Transfer with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/generative_text_style_transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/generative_text_style_transfer/</guid>
      <description>Natural Language Processing (NLP) is one area of deep learning that continues to make substantial, and often surprising, progress while also adding value to existing businesses. Supervised tasks like neural machine translation produce high quality, real-time results and Gmail&amp;rsquo;s predictive text feature often feels like magic. I have been most interested in recent applications of generative text models, such as using GPT-2 to play chess, write poetry, or create custom games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Statistical Consulting</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/lessons_from_statistical_consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/lessons_from_statistical_consulting/</guid>
      <description>The Stanford Statistics department offers a unique service; any and all researchers from across the university can come discuss their ideas with Master&amp;rsquo;s and PhD students. Eager to see whether I could apply my coursework to actual questions of experimental design, inference, and prediction, I signed up to be a consultant for the quarter. The experience was as challenging as I had expected, but the difficulty did not stem from choosing the best model or interpreting p-values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yield Curves in Dash</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/tradedash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/tradedash/</guid>
      <description>With a lot of recent focus on the direction of US interest rates and the likelihood of a recession, I thought I would play around with Treasury yield data to construct an easy way to keep an eye on how yield curves are changing. For those unfamiliar, yield curves are simple plots of the yield of a Treasury bill, note, or bond versus the maturities of the securities. The Treasury publishes the market yield for each maturity daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Personal Site From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/personal_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/personal_site/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit of time on my hands this summer and decided it would be a good time to build a personal website. I thought it would be a good place to display some work and encourage myself to write more. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how big a project this would be but tried out a bunch of options and ended up quite happy with Github Pages and a Flask static site generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/doing_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/doing_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy by William Janeway
Bill Janeway has a lot to say in this book, and he does so with dense and clear prose. In three points, this book makes clear:
 The innovation economy is a three player game among the state, the market economy, and financial institutions. The game is played with irreducible uncertainty, and playing by the rules of homo-economicus (some neoclassical rational agent) is not a successful strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Dream Machine</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/the_dream_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/the_dream_machine/</guid>
      <description>The Dream Machine by M. Mitchell Waldrop
In The Dream Machine, M. Mitchell Waldrop loosely tracks the career of J.C.R. Licklider, an MIT researcher and ARPA administrator who had a grand vision of human-computer symbiosis and networking.
More generally, Waldrop narrates the story of the modern computer, which one might simply see as a linear progression. Starting with WWII, mathematicians devised physical systems that could compute answers to specific questions, such as a mechanical differential analyzer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>