<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLP on Spencer Braun</title>
    <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NLP on Spencer Braun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spencerbraun.github.io/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NAACL 2022: Does Summary Evaluation Survive Translation?</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/does-summary-evaluation-survive-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/does-summary-evaluation-survive-translation/</guid>
      <description>Paper
Code
I recently presented a paper at the NAACL 2022 conference for work conducted with my colleagues at Primer in collaboration with Technische Universität Berlin. At Primer, summarization is a core task that our platform performs daily, but summarization evaluation is quite challenging even in English. Since we are often presented with data from many languages, we explored whether summarization datasets could remain useful under translation, as resources for non-English languages are far less plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socratic Models - AI Ensembles</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/socratic-models-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/socratic-models-applications/</guid>
      <description>The period of 2018-2020 was a critical time for progress in natural language processing. On the back of Transformers, a wave of value was created with products like text completion, sentiment analysis, entity recognition, and writing improvement tools. The process for creating these technologies would be familiar to data scientists across domains: collect and label data, train and fine-tune models, test different architectures, and optimize hyperparameters.
For those close to NLP research and development, the last year has presented a clear break from this incremental progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selectively Editable Language Models</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/selectively-editable-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/selectively-editable-language-models/</guid>
      <description>The post belows explains a project in editing language models I completed as part of Stanford’s course in natural language processing. If you want to skip to the point, the report and code are freely available.
Background: Taming Large Language Models Large language models have been an area of exciting development in the last few years, and we now have applications and entire companies built around their improving performance and utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Word Segmentation: Classic and Modern Methods</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/chinese-segmentation-classic-and-modern-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/chinese-segmentation-classic-and-modern-methods/</guid>
      <description>Part of the fun of NLP is the diversity of language structures that models must consider. Tools that are built in a monolingual context can easily fail to achieve more global utility. If you just work in English, you may find word embeddings fun and useful, but the German Komposita don’t fit neatly into our English-centric boxes. Similarly, once we leave the Latin alphabet, we acquire all sorts of new challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
