<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Spencer Braun</title>
    <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Spencer Braun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://spencerbraun.github.io/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Word Segmentation: Classic and Modern Methods</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/chinese-segmentation-classic-and-modern-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/chinese-segmentation-classic-and-modern-methods/</guid>
      <description>Part of the fun of NLP is the diversity of language structures that models must consider. Tools that are built in a monolingual context can easily fail to achieve more global utility. If you just work in English, you may find word embeddings fun and useful, but the German Komposita don’t fit neatly into our English-centric boxes. Similarly, once we leave the Latin alphabet, we acquire all sorts of new challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selectively Editable Language Models</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/selectively-editable-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/selectively-editable-language-models/</guid>
      <description>The post belows explains a project in editing language models I completed as part of Stanford’s course in natural language processing. If you want to skip to the point, the report and code are freely available.
Background: Taming Large Language Models Large language models have been an area of exciting development in the last few years, and we now have applications and entire companies built around their improving performance and utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Statistical Consulting</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/lessons_from_statistical_consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/lessons_from_statistical_consulting/</guid>
      <description>The Stanford Statistics department offers a unique service; any and all researchers from across the university can come discuss their ideas with Master&amp;rsquo;s and PhD students. Eager to see whether I could apply my coursework to actual questions of experimental design, inference, and prediction, I signed up to be a consultant for the quarter. The experience was as challenging as I had expected, but the difficulty did not stem from choosing the best model or interpreting p-values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/doing_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/doing_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy by William Janeway
Bill Janeway has a lot to say in this book, and he does so with dense and clear prose. In three points, this book makes clear:
 The innovation economy is a three player game among the state, the market economy, and financial institutions. The game is played with irreducible uncertainty, and playing by the rules of homo-economicus (some neoclassical rational agent) is not a successful strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Dream Machine</title>
      <link>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/the_dream_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerbraun.github.io/posts/the_dream_machine/</guid>
      <description>The Dream Machine by M. Mitchell Waldrop
In The Dream Machine, M. Mitchell Waldrop loosely tracks the career of J.C.R. Licklider, an MIT researcher and ARPA administrator who had a grand vision of human-computer symbiosis and networking.
More generally, Waldrop narrates the story of the modern computer, which one might simply see as a linear progression. Starting with WWII, mathematicians devised physical systems that could compute answers to specific questions, such as a mechanical differential analyzer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>