<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Spencer Braun</title>
    <link>/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Spencer Braun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy</title>
      <link>/posts/doing_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/doing_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Doing Capitalism in the Innovation Economy by William Janeway
Bill Janeway has a lot to say in this book, and he does so with dense and clear prose. In three points, this book makes clear:
 The innovation economy is a three player game among the state, the market economy, and financial institutions. The game is played with irreducible uncertainty, and playing by the rules of homo-economicus (some neoclassical rational agent) is not a successful strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Dream Machine</title>
      <link>/posts/the_dream_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the_dream_machine/</guid>
      <description>The Dream Machine by M. Mitchell Waldrop
In The Dream Machine, M. Mitchell Waldrop loosely tracks the career of J.C.R. Licklider, an MIT researcher and ARPA administrator who had a grand vision of human-computer symbiosis and networking.
More generally, Waldrop narrates the story of the modern computer, which one might simply see as a linear progression. Starting with WWII, mathematicians devised physical systems that could compute answers to specific questions, such as a mechanical differential analyzer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>